Over the last month, I've been playing around with TensorFlow and Keras,
在过去的一个月里，我一直在玩TensorFlow和Keras，
and I've noticed that a lot of the examples are these pre-canned demos that are great for showing you various features  but don't really show you how to use either of the frameworks.
我注意到很多示例都是预制的演示，非常适合展示各种功能，但并没有真正教你如何使用这些框架。
I'm hoping to change that without diving too deep into the guts of machine learning.
我希望能改变这一点，而不深入探讨机器学习的内部原理。
Over the next few episodes, I'm going to show you how to extract features from voice commands,
在接下来的几集节目中，我将向你展示如何从语音命令中提取特征，
use them to train a deep neural network, and then load that neural network onto a Raspberry Pi using TensorFlow Lite.
使用这些特征训练深度神经网络，然后使用TensorFlow Lite将该神经网络加载到Raspberry Pi上。
The idea is that we'll have a Pi constantly listening for audio, and when it hears our wake word, stop, it will toggle a pin.
我们的想法是让Pi一直监听音频，当它听到我们的唤醒词“停”时，它会切换一个引脚。
Please note that I'm not in any way a machine learning expert.
请注意，我并不是机器学习专家。
I'm still learning this as I go, but I wanted to share what I've found so far.
我也是在学习过程中，但我想分享我到目前为止的发现。
If you know of any better methods or techniques, please comment on this video.
如果你知道任何更好的方法或技术，请在此视频中评论。
I'd love to know if you think there's a better way to do things.
我很想知道你是否认为有更好的方法。
Most machine learning problems can be broken down into four steps.
大多数机器学习问题可以分为四个步骤。
The first is to collect a bunch of data that you think you'll need.
第一步是收集你认为需要的数据。
For the wake word, or hot word detection, we'll need a bunch of people saying many different words, including our target word.
对于唤醒词或热词检测，我们需要很多人说不同的词，包括我们的目标词。
The good news is that Google has already done this for us.
好消息是，Google已经为我们完成了这个任务。
We can use their speech commands data set to make life easier.
我们可以使用他们的语音命令数据集来简化工作。
Next, we need to figure out which features we can use in this data to discern one command from another.
接下来，我们需要弄清楚可以使用这些数据中的哪些特征来区分不同的命令。
After that, we'll build and train a model.
然后，我们将构建并训练一个模型。
Finally, we deploy that model to the Raspberry Pi, where we'll use TensorFlow Lite to help us determine if the target word was spoken in real time.
最后，我们将该模型部署到Raspberry Pi上，使用TensorFlow Lite帮助我们实时判断是否说出了目标词。
For this episode, I'd like to focus just on feature extraction.
在这一集节目中，我想专注于特征提取。
Note that you can't really use TensorFlow Lite to train a model.
注意，你不能真正使用TensorFlow Lite训练模型。
Its main purpose is to make predictions and inferences once you do have a fully trained model.
它的主要目的是在你有一个完全训练好的模型后进行预测和推理。
So for these first two episodes, we'll be working with Keras and TensorFlow in our desktop or laptop.
所以在前两集节目中，我们将在桌面或笔记本电脑上使用Keras和TensorFlow。
In fact, we won't even need TensorFlow until the next episode,
实际上，我们在下一集节目中才会真正使用TensorFlow，
and that's because we're going to be focused on just extracting features from audio data.
那是因为我们将专注于从音频数据中提取特征。
If you have not done so already, I recommend taking a look at my video for installing TensorFlow, Keras, and Jupyter Notebook.
如果你还没有这样做，我建议你查看我关于安装TensorFlow、Keras和Jupyter Notebook的视频。
We'll be needing them throughout this process.
在整个过程中我们都需要它们。
If you have a Google account, you can also head to colab.research.google.com to run Jupyter Notebook in the cloud.
如果你有一个Google账户，你也可以前往colab.research.google.com在云端运行Jupyter Notebook。
There is no setup involved and it's free.
无需设置且免费使用。
Note that all files are stored on your Google Drive, so it might take some extra work to move very large datasets in and out of your workspace.
注意，所有文件都存储在你的Google Drive上，因此将大型数据集移入移出工作区可能需要额外工作。
Also note that loading files into Colab requires different commands than doing it locally on your own machine.
还要注意，将文件加载到Colab中需要使用不同于本地计算机的命令。
To start, we need to download the dataset.
首先，我们需要下载数据集。
Search for the Google Speech Commands dataset.
搜索Google Speech Commands数据集。
I've had the best luck finding it on the TensorFlow GitHub repo docs page.
我发现最好的办法是到TensorFlow的GitHub仓库文档页面上找。
I'll grab version 0.02, which seems to have worked well for this application.
我会下载版本0.02，这个版本在这个应用中效果很好。
Note that it's a pretty big download, and if you want, you can contribute your own voice to the dataset while you wait.
注意，这个下载文件相当大，在下载的同时，你可以为数据集贡献自己的语音。
When it's done downloading, unzip the files to somewhere on your computer.
下载完成后，将文件解压到你计算机上的某个位置。
I'll keep mine in a datasets folder near my other Python projects.
我会把它放在我的其他Python项目附近的datasets文件夹中。
Feel free to browse through the files in the dataset.
随意浏览数据集中的文件。
We'll pick stop as our wake word.
我们将选择“停”作为我们的唤醒词。
If we play them, it's just a collection of recordings from various people saying, stop.
如果我们播放它们，它们就是来自不同人说“停”的录音集合。
You'll want to copy down the absolute path to your Speech Commands dataset.
你需要记录下Speech Commands数据集的绝对路径。
We'll need it in a minute.
我们一会儿会用到它。
If you want to create your own wake word, you'll first need to make a new folder in this dataset.
如果你想创建自己的唤醒词，首先需要在这个数据集中创建一个新文件夹。
Then record yourself or other people saying that wake word.
然后录下你自己或其他人说的那个唤醒词。
You'll want the audio clips to be exactly one second for them to work in the rest of this project.
你需要确保音频片段正好是一秒钟长，这样才能在这个项目的其余部分中工作。
The bigger variety of audio you can get, the better.
音频种类越多越好。
Ideally, you'll want at least a few hundred different recordings.
理想情况下，你至少需要几百个不同的录音。
There's a good bit of code involved in these steps, so I'm going to briefly go over each chunk of code.
这些步骤涉及到很多代码，所以我会简要介绍每段代码。
If you'd like to take your time to go over the code, you can find it in a link in the description.
如果你想仔细研究这些代码，可以在描述中的链接中找到它们。
Start a new Jupyter Notebook session using TensorFlow or TensorFlow GPU.
用TensorFlow或TensorFlow GPU启动一个新的Jupyter Notebook会话。
In a new notebook, let's import the necessary packages.
在新笔记本中，让我们导入必要的包。
We'll need OS for dealing with files, Librosa for loading and resampling WAV files,
我们需要用到OS来处理文件，用Librosa来加载和重采样WAV文件，
Random for shuffling data, NumPy for dealing with matrices, Matplotlib for graphing things,
用Random来随机数据，用NumPy来处理矩阵，用Matplotlib来绘图，
and Python Speech Features for extracting audio features.
以及用Python Speech Features来提取音频特征。
Note that if you do not have one of these packages,
注意，如果你没有其中一个包，
you can install it from within Jupyter Notebook by typing exclamation point pip install and the name of the package.
可以在Jupyter Notebook中输入感叹号pip install加包名来安装它。
From there, we'll use join to construct the path to our data set.
接下来，我们会用join来构建数据集的路径。
Let's print them out to make sure we can see all of the speech directories.
让我们打印出来确保可以看到所有的语音目录。
We can pick just a few words to train with, but I'm going to train with all of the words.
我们可以选择几个词来训练，但我打算用所有的词来训练。
We'll tell it to recognize only one of the words in a later step.
我们会在后面的步骤中告诉它只识别其中一个词。
The background noise seems to mess things up for me, so I'm going to leave it off.
背景噪音对我来说似乎会搞乱事情，所以我会把它关掉。
In theory, you could mix these noises in with the other speech samples to train a model that could automatically filter out various background sounds.
理论上，你可以将这些噪音与其他语音样本混合，训练一个可以自动滤除各种背景声音的模型。
Let's print out the number of files in each target directory.
让我们打印出每个目标目录中的文件数量。
Each word has a few thousand samples, as you can see.
如你所见，每个词都有几千个样本。
Let's set a few parameters for the rest of this script.
让我们为这个脚本的其余部分设置一些参数。
We'll want to create features for all of the target words, even if we just pick out one target word later.
我们需要为所有目标词创建特征，即使我们稍后只选择一个目标词。
At the end of the script, we'll have a collection of features,
在脚本的最后，我们将有一个特征集合，
essentially matrices that resemble images, that will store into an NPZ file.
基本上类似于图像的矩阵，将它们存储到一个NPZ文件中。
In practice, you'd want to use all the data you have available.
实际上，你会想要使用所有可用的数据。
However, it can take hours to extract features and train using 100,000 samples.
然而，提取特征和使用100,000个样本进行训练可能需要数小时。
So I find it much easier to work with a random subset of data.
所以我发现使用随机子集数据更容易工作。
I'll use 10%.
我会使用10%。
This should only be used for initial prototypes to make sure that things are working.
这只应该用于初步原型，以确保事情正常工作。
You'll want to go back to the full 100% of data when you train your final model.
当你准备训练最终模型时，你需要回到100%的数据。
We also want to set aside 10% of our data for cross-validation and 10% for testing.
我们还需要将10%的数据留作交叉验证和10%的数据留作测试。
I'll talk about that in a minute.
我稍后会谈到这一点。
While the WAV files are recorded with a 16 kHz sampling rate,
虽然WAV文件是以16kHz的采样率录制的，
we'll be able to get our final model to run faster if we can use a lower sampling rate, like 8 kHz.
但如果我们使用较低的采样率（如8kHz），我们将能够让最终模型运行得更快。
We'll set the number of Mell frequency sepstral coefficients to 16 and the length of these MFCCs to 16.
我们将梅尔频率倒谱系数的数量设置为16，这些MFCC的长度为16。
I'll also talk about why MFCCs make for good features in a minute, but let's continue with getting raw data from our files.
我稍后会谈到为什么MFCC是良好的特征，但让我们继续从文件中获取原始数据。
Next, we're going to create a list of all the file names with their full path.
接下来，我们将创建一个包含全路径的文件名列表。
This will allow us to load each one and extract the features automatically.
这将允许我们加载每一个并自动提取特征。
In addition, we want to create a Y array.
此外，我们需要创建一个Y数组。
This array holds the ground truth or actual values.
这个数组保存了实际值或真实值。
Since this is a supervised learning exercise where we classify signals,
因为这是一个监督学习练习，我们在训练步骤中需要信号的标签。
we'll need the labels for the signals during the training step.
在训练阶段我们应该为信号添加标签
We can arbitrarily assign values, but they should be consistent.
我们可以任意分配值，但它们应该一致。
We'll assign numbers to the words in alphabetical order.
我们将按字母顺序分配单词的编号。
Backward is 0, bed is 1, bird is 2, and so on.
Backward是0，bed是1，bird是2，依此类推。
Let's print out Y.
让我们打印出Y。
We see that it's a collection of arrays,
我们看到它是一个数组集合，
and each array is simply the number we assigned to the target word.
每个数组只是我们分配给目标词的编号。
So there are 1664 zeros in this first array,
所以在这个第一个数组中有1664个0，
which correspond to the 1664 samples of people saying the word backward.
这对应于1664个说backward的样本。
Similarly, there are 2014 ones in the next array,
类似地，在下一个数组中有2014个1，
which correspond to the samples of bed.
这对应于bed的样本。
We then flatten these arrays so they're just one long list rather than a collection of arrays.
然后我们将这些数组扁平化，使它们成为一个长列表，而不是数组的集合。
The next part is easiest to describe with a diagram.
接下来的部分最好用图表描述。
We'll use the Python zip command to link each file name with its associated Y value.
我们将使用Python的zip命令将每个文件名与其关联的Y值连接起来。
There are a lot more files than this, but go with me here.
虽然有更多文件，但请跟着我。
We then randomly shuffle the file names,
然后我们随机打乱文件名，
and notice that the Y values stayed linked to the individual names.
注意，Y值仍然链接到各个名称。
We can then unzip the two lists to separate file names and Y, but their ordering will remain.
然后我们解压这两个列表以分离文件名和Y值，但它们的顺序将保持不变。
Finally, we will take the first 10% of the data and set it aside to be our cross-validation set.
最后，我们将前10%的数据留作交叉验证集。
This will be useful in testing the model to see how well it performs during training.
这将在训练期间测试模型的表现时很有用。
Then we set aside another 10% as test data.
然后我们将另外10%的数据留作测试数据。
We should only test with this data when we're done tweaking the model and hyperparameters.
我们在调整模型和超参数完成后才会使用这些数据进行测试。
We leave the rest of the data alone to be used as training data.
我们将剩余的数据作为训练数据。
Note that cross-validation and test sets can be anywhere from 10% to 20% of the data each.
注意，交叉验证集和测试集可以占总数据的10%到20%。
Feel free to pick something in that range depending on how much total data you have available.
根据你拥有的总数据量，自由选择该范围内的比例。
Back to our code, we can see how those steps were accomplished in these cells.
回到我们的代码，我们可以看到这些步骤在这些单元格中是如何完成的。
We zip the file names and Y array together, shuffle them and unzip them.
我们将文件名和Y数组一起压缩，打乱它们，然后解压它们。
Because I don't want to take a lot of time training a prototype model,
因为我不想花太多时间训练原型模型，
I'm going to only work with 10% of the total data for now.
所以我现在只使用总数据的10%。
It's really important that you come back to this and use all the data when you're ready to train your model for testing and deployment.
当你准备好训练测试和部署的模型时，务必要使用所有的数据。
Here, we break apart the file name list and ground truth list into separate validation, test and training sets.
在这里，我们将文件名列表和真实值列表分解成单独的验证集、测试集和训练集。
We're now ready to extract features from these WAV files.
现在我们准备从这些WAV文件中提取特征。
When it comes to feature extraction, it's a good idea to do some research on what other people have done.
在特征提取方面，研究其他人的做法是个好主意。
This is where I found out about MFCCs and from what I read,
这就是我发现MFCCs的地方，据我所读到的，
transforming audio into the Mell frequency sepstral coefficients
将音频转换为梅尔频率倒谱系数
seems to be very popular in machine learning for speech recognition.
在语音识别的机器学习中似乎非常流行。
To calculate the MFCCs, we take a small time slice of our audio waveform and compute the fast Fourier transform.
为了计算MFCCs，我们取音频波形的一小段时间片并计算快速傅里叶变换。
This gives us the amount of power at each frequency of that time slice.
这给我们每个频率在该时间片中的功率量。
Then we apply a set of filters to that fast Fourier transform spectrum.
然后我们将一组滤波器应用于快速傅里叶变换频谱。
Note that these filters are spaced in such a way to represent how humans perceive sound.
注意，这些滤波器的间隔方式代表了人类感知声音的方式。
Generally, the filters are linearly spaced below 1 kilohertz and logarithmically spaced above 1 kilohertz.
通常，滤波器在1千赫以下是线性间隔，在1千赫以上是对数间隔。
We then sum up the power found in each filter to get a number representing the energy under that filter.
然后我们将每个滤波器中的功率相加，得到一个代表该滤波器下能量的数字。
Note that most implementations of MFCC use 26 filters for voice.
注意，大多数MFCC实现使用26个滤波器来处理语音。
From there, you'll want to compute the log of each value in the vector.
然后，你需要对向量中的每个值取对数。
After that, we compute the discrete cosine transform of the 26 log filter bank energies.
之后，我们计算26个对数滤波器能量的离散余弦变换。
The DCT works much like the Fourier transform but operates on real valued signals and does a better job of emphasizing the low frequency components.
DCT的工作方式类似于傅里叶变换，但它作用于实数信号，并且更好地强调低频分量。
If you start with 26 elements in the filter bank energies,
如果你从26个滤波器能量元素开始，
you should end up with 26 sepstral coefficients.
你应该会得到26个倒谱系数。
The lower coefficients, like elements 0, 1, and 2, contain information about the general shape of the audio spectrum in that time slice.
较低的系数，如元素0、1和2，包含该时间片中音频频谱的一般形状信息。
As you go up in the coefficients, you start to get into the finer details of the audio spectrum.
随着系数的增加，你会开始得到音频频谱的更精细细节。
For speech analysis, you normally want to throw away the zeroth element and anything after element 13.
对于语音分析，你通常希望丢弃第零元素和第13元素之后的所有元素。
Above the 13th element is usually noise and audio artifacts that don't correlate to speech much.
第13元素以上的通常是噪音和音频伪影，与语音相关性不大。
So we've computed the MFCCs for the first time slice of our audio file.
因此，我们计算了音频文件第一个时间片的MFCCs。
Notice that I've flipped the vector around so that the first element is on the bottom and the highest element is on the top.
注意，我将向量翻转，使第一个元素在底部，最高的元素在顶部。
You'll see why in a second.
你马上就会明白为什么。
Also, after some testing, I found that for the model I plan to train, having 16 elements seems to work the best.
此外，经过一些测试，我发现对于我计划训练的模型，16个元素效果最好。
Note that this might not be universally true.
注意，这可能不是普遍适用的。
You might be able to get good or better accuracy with a different neural network and only 12 elements.
你可能能够使用不同的神经网络和只有12个元素来获得良好的或更好的准确性。
The point is to keep trying and experimenting with things to find something that works.
关键是不断尝试和实验，找到有效的东西。
We then slide our window over a bit on the waveform and compute the MFCCs from that time slice.
然后我们在波形上滑动窗口，并从该时间片计算MFCCs。
Keep going until we've obtained all the MFCCs for the whole waveform.
继续进行，直到我们获得整个波形的所有MFCCs。
At this point, we have a two-dimensional array of MFCC values.
此时，我们有一个二维的MFCC值数组。
One way to view this matrix is as an image.
一种查看这个矩阵的方法是将其视为图像。
The x-axis here is the time.
这里的x轴是时间。
Each column of pixels corresponds to one of the time slices we took.
每列像素对应我们取的一个时间片。
The y-axis is the MFCCs, so there should be 16 total rows.
y轴是MFCCs，所以应该总共有16行。
The colors give us a relative representation of the value of each coefficient.
颜色为我们提供了每个系数值的相对表示。
The bottom row, or zeroth coefficient, is dark because they're all large negative values compared to the rest.
最底行或第零系数是深色的，因为它们与其余的相比都是大的负值。
This is an example of MFCCs computed from someone saying the word stop.
这是一个人说“停”这个词时计算的MFCCs示例。
If we compute the MFCCs for someone saying zero, you can see how it produces a slightly different image.
如果我们计算一个人说“零”的MFCCs，你会看到它生成的图像略有不同。
It might be tough for a human to see these differences, but a machine can do that quite easily.
人类可能很难看到这些差异，但机器可以轻松做到。
So we will actually use a neural network that classifies images to help discern these different wake words.
所以我们实际上将使用一个神经网络来帮助区分这些不同的唤醒词。
If you'd like to learn more about MFCCs, check out this post on the Practical Cryptography site.
如果你想了解更多关于MFCCs的信息，请查看Practical Cryptography网站上的这篇文章。
In fact, this post was written by the same author of the Python Speech Features Library that we'll be using.
事实上，这篇文章的作者也是我们将使用的Python Speech Features库的作者。
Let's go back to our code.
让我们回到代码。
We'll make a quick function that loads the wave file from a given path and resamples it to 8,000 samples per second.
我们将编写一个快速函数，从给定路径加载波形文件并重新采样到8000个样本每秒。
We'll use Librosa to do that, since it can load and resample in one line of code.
我们将使用Librosa来完成，因为它可以在一行代码中加载和重新采样。
Then we'll use the Python Speech Features MFCC function to create a set of MFCCs from that waveform.
然后我们将使用Python Speech Features的MFCC函数从该波形中创建一组MFCCs。
Feel free to play around with these parameters.
随意调整这些参数。
I wanted to keep the number of MFCC sets produced low, so I widened the window from 25 milliseconds to 256 milliseconds.
我想保持产生的MFCC集合数量较少，所以我将窗口从25毫秒扩大到256毫秒。
I also increased the distance between the windows to 50 milliseconds.
我还将窗口之间的距离增加到50毫秒。
We want the first 16 MFCCs from this, and we'll use the default 26 filters.
我们需要从中获得前16个MFCCs，并使用默认的26个滤波器。
The number of samples to use for the FFT is dependent on the size of the window,
用于FFT的样本数取决于窗口的大小，
so I had to increase that to 2,048 from the default 512.
所以我将它从默认的512增加到2048。
I found that the pre-emphasis filter didn't make too much of a difference, so I disabled it.
我发现预加重滤波器没有太大影响，所以我禁用了它。
You might have better luck with it on.
你可能会有更好的运气。
You can supposedly add a liftering operation on the final coefficients to help make them more robust against noise.
据说你可以对最终系数添加liftering操作，以帮助它们更能抵抗噪音。
That's one more operation that I didn't need in this basic prototype, so I disabled liftering.
这是我在这个基本原型中不需要的另一操作，所以我禁用了liftering。
Since the zero-width elements of the MFCCs are often thrown out,
由于MFCCs的零宽元素通常被丢弃，
this function can offer to replace them with something that gives total energy in that frame.
该函数可以选择用一个表示该帧总能量的值来替换它们。
Once again, I didn't find that necessary with this prototype, so I turned that feature off.
在这个原型中我发现这并不必要，所以我关闭了这个功能。
Finally, applying a window function like a Hamming or Hanning window can help prevent the Fast Fourier Transform operation produce unwanted artifacts in the higher frequencies.
最后，应用像Hamming或Hanning窗口这样的窗口函数可以帮助防止快速傅里叶变换操作在高频率中产生不必要的伪影。
Let's test this on some files.
让我们在一些文件上测试一下。
I'll take the first 500 samples from the training set and display the shape of their MFCC matrices.
我将从训练集中的前500个样本中获取并显示其MFCC矩阵的形状。
Each audio file should produce 16 sets of 16 coefficients.
每个音频文件应该产生16组16个系数。
As you can see, a few of the audio files seem to have been corrupted or not fully one second long.
如你所见，一些音频文件似乎已损坏或不足一秒长。
If we count these up and divide by 500,
如果我们将这些数据计算并除以500，
we can conclude that about 10% of all the audio samples have this problem.
我们可以得出结论，约10%的音频样本有这个问题。
Let's test a few of these.
让我们测试一些。
Here's a quick script that uses the play sound library to play the audio sample, display the MFCCs and resulting image,
这是一个快速脚本，使用play sound库播放音频样本，显示MFCCs和生成的图像，
as well as give us what word it's supposed to be.
并告诉我们它应该是什么词。
After testing a number of these,
在测试了许多这些样本后，
I found that many of them were cut off or completely inaudible.
我发现许多样本被切断或完全无法听见。
There are a number of ways to deal with bad data in a set with machine learning.
在有问题的数据集中处理不良数据有多种方法。
If the sample isn't quite long enough,
如果样本不够长，
you can append values that look like data found within the sample,
你可以追加看起来像样本内数据的值，
something that approximates silence or white noise.
比如接近静音或白噪声的东西。
You can also just drop the sample completely, which is the easiest thing to do.
你也可以完全删除样本，这是最简单的做法。
Since only about 10% of the samples are problematic for this data set,
由于这个数据集中只有约10%的样本有问题，
I'm just going to drop any of them that don't produce exactly 16 sets of coefficients.
所以我将删除任何未生成准确16组系数的样本。
So we write another function that does exactly that.
所以我们编写了一个函数来做这件事。
It makes sure the file ends with .WAVE,
它确保文件以.WAVE结尾，
calculates the MFCCs and drops the sample and corresponding label from the Y vectors if it's not long enough.
计算MFCCs并在样本不足长时从Y向量中删除样本及其对应的标签。
We then run that function on each of our training, validation and test sets.
然后我们在每个训练集、验证集和测试集上运行该函数。
This might take a few minutes, so go make a sandwich or something.
这可能需要几分钟，所以去做个三明治吧。
When it's done, you can see that it removed about 10% of samples from the set, which I'm okay with.
完成后，你会看到它从集合中删除了约10%的样本，我对此没有问题。
Finally, we use the NumPy saveZ function to store these massive arrays into an NPZ file.
最后，我们使用NumPy的saveZ函数将这些巨大的数组存储到一个NPZ文件中。
This will allow us to load our saved features and corresponding labels in a future step when we're ready to do the actual machine learning.
这将允许我们在未来步骤中加载保存的特征和相应的标签，当我们准备进行实际机器学习时。
To load the features, we just call numpy.load and give it the location of the file.
要加载特征，只需调用numpy.load并给出文件位置。
We can then list out the available arrays and see the number of samples in each one.
然后我们可以列出可用的数组并查看每个数组中的样本数量。
If we print the Y validation set, you can see all of the labels that we have stored in that set.
如果我们打印Y验证集，你会看到我们在该集中存储的所有标签。
Next time, we'll use these stored features to train a neural network that will classify our wake word from all the other words.
下次我们将使用这些存储的特征来训练一个神经网络，将我们的唤醒词与所有其他词区分开来。
Remember that this isn't a very robust model, it's just something to get us started.
记住，这不是一个非常健壮的模型，这只是一个开始。
Please subscribe if you'd like to keep up with these videos and happy hacking.
如果你想继续观看这些视频，请订阅，祝你黑客快乐。